window.examQuestions = [
    { "id": 1, "question": "What is the name of nominee Director from NABARD on our Board of Directors", "answer": "Shri N.L.Sahoo" },
    { "id": 2, "question": "What is an inchoate instrument", "answer": "Incomplete" },
    { "id": 3, "question": "A subscribe exit from Atal Pension Yojana if he fails to pay subscription amount continuously for....... months", "answer": "24 months" },
    { "id": 4, "question": "Expand CIF in NRLM", "answer": "Community Investment Fund" },
    { "id": 5, "question": "Break-even point means", "answer": "A stage at which unit runs on no profit and no loss basis" },
    { "id": 6, "question": "Provision of standard loan shown in balance sheet in schedule......", "answer": "Schedule V" },
    { "id": 7, "question": "Under which Act RBI issues instructions on Integrated ombudsman scheme?", "answer": "Banking Regulation Act" },
    { "id": 8, "question": "What is Liquidity risk?", "answer": "Is the risk of loss resulting from the inability to meet payment obligations in full and on time" },
    { "id": 9, "question": "Mortgage defined under which act?", "answer": "Transfer of Properties Act, 1882" },
    { "id": 10, "question": "In Agri infra fund maximum amount of loan eligible for subsidy is up to Rs......... crores", "answer": "up to Rs.2 crores" },
    { "id": 11, "question": "Lok Adalat were established under which Act?", "answer": "Legal Services Authorities Act, 1987" },
    { "id": 12, "question": "If a Power of Attorney holder expires after signing a cheque, will bank pay if the cheque is presented for payment after the death of power of attorney holder?", "answer": "Not pay" },
    { "id": 13, "question": "Maximum amount of loan that can be given in Saral Vyapar loan scheme", "answer": "3cr urban/Metro" },
    { "id": 14, "question": "Garnishee order issued by ...... where bank is called........", "answer": "Court, garnishee" },
    { "id": 15, "question": "In case of dishonor of cheque, maximum punishment for imprisonment is...... years", "answer": "maximum two years of imprisonment" },
    { "id": 16, "question": "What % of interest is charged in DRI scheme", "answer": "4% p.a" },
    { "id": 17, "question": "Bank should not offer gift to customer more than Rs. :", "answer": "250/-" },
    { "id": 18, "question": "What is the maximum amount of loan that can be sanctioned under Small Roadways Transport Operators scheme", "answer": "1cr" },
    { "id": 19, "question": "What is the amount of loan under PMSVANIDHI-3rd Tranche", "answer": "Rs.50000" },
    { "id": 20, "question": "What is the number of members of SHG under DAY NRLM", "answer": "10-20 members" },
    { "id": 21, "question": "C' stands for in MCLR", "answer": "Cost" },
    { "id": 22, "question": "Please inform the name of Form required for cancellation of nomination by locker hirer", "answer": "Form: SL 2" },
    { "id": 23, "question": "Full form of CKYC-R", "answer": "Central KYC Records Registry" },
    { "id": 24, "question": "What is general crossing", "answer": "Drawing two transverse parallel lines on the face of the cheque" },
    { "id": 25, "question": "Fine if counterfeit note is found in soiled note packet.", "answer": "Penalty equal to the value of/ denomination of counterfeit note plus recovery of loss" },
    { "id": 26, "question": "Transaction code for multi-city SB cheque", "answer": "31" },
    { "id": 27, "question": "Margin in car loan", "answer": "15%of on-road price" },
    { "id": 28, "question": "What is negative Net working capital?", "answer": "Current liabilities are more than Current Assets" },
    { "id": 29, "question": "A want to open an account jointly with his relative but wants that during his lifetime he should operate the account and after his death his relative to operate the account. What is mode of operation:", "answer": "Former or survivor" },
    { "id": 30, "question": "If sanction limit is 5 lakhs, stocks is six lakhs, margin is 25%, what is the DP?", "answer": "4.5 lakhs" },
    { "id": 31, "question": "In IFSC S stands for..........", "answer": "System" },
    { "id": 32, "question": "What is an endorsement?", "answer": "Signing on the back of cheque for the purpose of negotiation" },
    { "id": 33, "question": "What is the optional limit of cheque under Positive Pay system", "answer": "Rs.50,000" },
    { "id": 34, "question": "What is honorarium payable to Guest faculty", "answer": "Rs.1000 for one session" },
    { "id": 35, "question": "Banking is defined under which Act?", "answer": "Banking Regulation Act" },
    { "id": 36, "question": "Customer deposited cheque for collection but before that he wants cash equivalent to the amount of the cheque. What is the status of of collecting banker?", "answer": "Holder for value" },
    { "id": 37, "question": "Nodal Agency of PMEGP Scheme?", "answer": "KVIC" },
    { "id": 38, "question": "What is the minimum age and education required in PMFME Scheme?", "answer": "18 years and 8th standard" },
    { "id": 39, "question": "In case of a joint account with either or survivor clause who will take the payment after maturity of Fixed Deposit?", "answer": "Survivor" },
    { "id": 40, "question": "Limitation in Demand Promissory Note.", "answer": "3 years from the date of DPN" },
    { "id": 41, "question": "In Sec. 269T of Income Tax, the cash payment in FD can be made up to Rs........", "answer": "below 20000" },
    { "id": 42, "question": "Loan sanction against the LIC Policies on the basis....value?", "answer": "Surrender value" },
    { "id": 43, "question": "DD of which amount cannot be paid in cash:", "answer": "Rs. 20,000/- and above" },
    { "id": 44, "question": "If bank receives garnishee order, then what will be relationship between bank and customer?", "answer": "Bank: Debtor, Customer: Judgment Debtor" },
    { "id": 45, "question": "Banking Ombudsman complaint should be closed within..... days after receiving the complaint in CMS portal by Respondent", "answer": "30 days" },
    { "id": 46, "question": "Agricultural loan up Rs....... can be sanctioned without any collateral security:", "answer": "Rs.2.00 lakh" },
    { "id": 47, "question": "If Net Working Capital is 8, Current Liability is 32, what is Current Ratio", "answer": "1.25:1" },
    { "id": 48, "question": "Door step banking- what should be the age of Senior citizen:", "answer": "70 years and above" },
    { "id": 49, "question": "If bank stamp is affixed on the face of cheque, crossing is called:", "answer": "Special Crossing" },
    { "id": 50, "question": "What is Gresham Law:", "answer": "Old currency keeps out new currency." },
    { "id": 51, "question": "Too much money for too less goods is termed as ......", "answer": "Inflation" },
    { "id": 52, "question": "Claimed in DRT:", "answer": "Rs.20 lakhs and above" },
    { "id": 53, "question": "In a society A/c if one of the signatory dies and a cheque signed by him during his life time is presented after his death, can bank pay the cheque?", "answer": "Yes" },
    { "id": 54, "question": "Priority Sector target of weaker section.........", "answer": "15% of ANBC or CEOBE whichever is higher" },
    { "id": 55, "question": "SLR is under which section:", "answer": "Sec. 24 of BR Act" },
    { "id": 56, "question": "Possession a cheque for a consideration:", "answer": "Holder in due" },
    { "id": 57, "question": "Devaluation means:", "answer": "Reduction in the value of a currency" },
    { "id": 58, "question": "Banker-customer relationship in overdraft:", "answer": "Creditor-Banker" },
    { "id": 59, "question": "Turn over limit of small enterprises:", "answer": "Above Rs.10 and up to Rs.100 Cr." },
    { "id": 60, "question": "In Gold loan which charge is created?", "answer": "Pledge" },
    { "id": 61, "question": "PMFME scheme-admissible subsidy to SHG", "answer": "35% of project cost" },
    { "id": 62, "question": "Payment gateway is related to.........", "answer": "A network through which payments are transferred from one bank account to other bank" },
    { "id": 63, "question": "In a JLG what should be the number of member", "answer": "Minimum 4 and maximum 10" },
    { "id": 64, "question": "Expand PIDPI", "answer": "Public Interest Disclosure and Protection to Informers" },
    { "id": 65, "question": "Interest subsidy in DAY- NRLM up to loan of Rs.3 lakhs", "answer": "0.07" },
    { "id": 66, "question": "Demand Notice period according to Sarfaesi act", "answer": "60 days" },
    { "id": 67, "question": "Interest on DEAF Account-", "answer": "3%" },
    { "id": 68, "question": "Schedule 14 of balance sheet:", "answer": "Other income" },
    { "id": 69, "question": "Provision is shown in which schedule in Bank Balance sheet", "answer": "Schedule-5" },
    { "id": 70, "question": "What is limitation period in court decree:", "answer": "12 years" },
    { "id": 71, "question": "What is the notice period given to drawer of a cheque by the payee under section 138 of NI Act", "answer": "15 days" },
    { "id": 72, "question": "What is the rate of provision in Commercial Real Estate (CRE)", "answer": "0.01" },
    { "id": 73, "question": "What is current bank rate", "answer": "5.75%" },
    { "id": 74, "question": "Pre-paid expenses is categorized under", "answer": "Current Asset" },
    { "id": 75, "question": "What is the power of a scale II manager to settle a deceased claim case", "answer": "2 Lakh" },
    { "id": 76, "question": "Maximum amount of loan hat can be given in Agriculture Infrastructure under Priority Sector", "answer": "100 crores" },
    { "id": 77, "question": "In small BSBDA accounts maximum deposits in a financial year can be up to Rs.......", "answer": "1 lakh" },
    { "id": 78, "question": "In case of locker joint a/c operations, how many nominations allowed:", "answer": "More than one" },
    { "id": 79, "question": "In PMSBY what premium amount goes to insurance company:", "answer": "Rs. 18" },
    { "id": 80, "question": "What is the limitation period of mortgage:", "answer": "12 years from the date mortgaged money falls due" },
    { "id": 81, "question": "Central Govt. shareholding as on 31/03/2025 balance sheet of the bank:", "answer": "50% (Rupees four hundred eighty seven crore seventy five lakh thirty one thousand six" },
    { "id": 82, "question": "Nominee Director from RBI in UPGB:", "answer": "Shri Manmohan" },
    { "id": 83, "question": "Single Nodal Agency for PMEGP:", "answer": "KVIC" },
    { "id": 84, "question": "In GSTIN number; the last digit indicates for", "answer": "Check-sum" },
    { "id": 85, "question": "On a cheque if the amount or name of payee or a special crossing is changed, this will be called:", "answer": "Material alteration" },
    { "id": 86, "question": "Loan for harvester falls under which category:", "answer": "Farm Mechanisation (Farm credit)" },
    { "id": 87, "question": "Under CGTMSE, claim will be lodged after how many years of Account becoming NPA:", "answer": "3 years (maximum within 3 years)" },
    { "id": 88, "question": "In a medium risk account KYC updation shall be done after every......years", "answer": "Medium risk-8 years" },
    { "id": 89, "question": "In IRDAI, R-denotes:", "answer": "Regulatory" },
    { "id": 90, "question": "What is the amount of allowance paid to any office attendants/ drivers for shoes and socks:", "answer": "One pair of shoes and 2 pair of socks per year @ 1,950/- each" },
    { "id": 91, "question": "In suspicious transaction, the principal Officer's role is to inform the FIU IND within....... days of confirmation of suspicious transaction", "answer": "7 days of confirmation" },
    { "id": 92, "question": "In case of Term deposit premature closure no interest shall be paid if the FD is closed within......days of date of opening", "answer": "7 days" },
    { "id": 93, "question": "Which method is used for working capital assessment for loan limit up to Rs. 5 Cr.:", "answer": "Turnover Method" },
    { "id": 94, "question": "Who is the beneficiary of Letter of Credit", "answer": "Exporter/ Seller" },
    { "id": 95, "question": "Interest rate on Sukanya Samridhhi Scheme is decided by", "answer": "Central Govt." },
    { "id": 96, "question": "Where the SARFAESI Act cannot applied", "answer": "Loan on Agri Lands" },
    { "id": 97, "question": "What is the Legal Amount in instrument", "answer": "Amount in Words" },
    { "id": 98, "question": "What is the maximum tenor for Car loan", "answer": "84 months" },
    { "id": 99, "question": "Maximum education loan under Priority sector Lending:", "answer": "Rs. 25 Lacs" },
    { "id": 100, "question": "What is the ratio between Central and state PMFME Scheme: Coverage of states/ UT's and Funding Pattern:", "answer": "60/40" },
    { "id": 101, "question": "How many soiled notes can be exchanged in a day at branch counter", "answer": "20 pieces with maximum 5000 per day, banks should exchange them over the counter," },
    { "id": 102, "question": "Full form of NCLAT", "answer": "National Company Law Appellate Tribunal" },
    { "id": 103, "question": "Under which section of act bank cannot grant loan to the director", "answer": "Section 20 (1), BR Act, 1949" },
    { "id": 104, "question": "What is the minimum claim amount for filing the case in DRT court for recovery", "answer": "Rs. 20 lacs" },
    { "id": 105, "question": "What is the provision of NPA portion calculation of Doubtful 1-Secured Category:", "answer": "25% for secured portion" },
    { "id": 106, "question": "Governing Body of PM-SvaNidhi scheme is", "answer": "Ministry of Housing & Urban Affairs" },
    { "id": 107, "question": "If A & B are joint a/c holders with C nominee, if A dies who will receive the payment after maturity", "answer": "Legal heirs of A and B" },
    { "id": 108, "question": "What is the premium of PMJJBY if a person is enrolled in the scheme during September to November quarter:", "answer": "Rs.342" },
    { "id": 109, "question": "What is the threshold limit for declaring a defaulter of the bank as willful defaulter?", "answer": "25 lakhs" },
    { "id": 110, "question": "After what period a substandard asset is converted in doubtful 1 category:", "answer": "After 12 M" },
    { "id": 111, "question": "What are the categories of NPA:", "answer": "Sub-standard, doubtful and loss" },
    { "id": 112, "question": "What is the full form of FATF", "answer": "Financial Action Task Force" },
    { "id": 113, "question": "Counterfeit notes shall be reported through a consolidated at the end of month if up to...notes are received in a single transaction at branch counter", "answer": "Up to 4 counterfeit notes if detected in a single transaction" },
    { "id": 114, "question": "KYC related documents should be submitted within how many days in small BSBD a/c:", "answer": "12 months (+ 12M if provides evidence of applying for OVD)." },
    { "id": 115, "question": "Signing on the back of the cheque for the purpose of negotiation is called.........", "answer": "Endorsement" },
    { "id": 116, "question": "In case of wrongful dishonor of cheque, bank will be liable to:", "answer": "Bank will be liable to true owner of the cheque/drawer" },
    { "id": 117, "question": "Cash Reserve Ratio is calculated on:", "answer": "Net Demand and Time Liabilities of the bank. Current CRR is 3.75%" },
    { "id": 118, "question": "Premium of DICGC Coverage is paid by whom:", "answer": "Respective banks" },
    { "id": 119, "question": "Nomination is allowed in case of:", "answer": "Individual/ joint/ sole proprietor" },
    { "id": 120, "question": "Within how many days a discounted bill becomes NPA when it is due:", "answer": "90 days from the due date of Bill" }
];
